ANS Record Group 1: Administrative, 1853-ongoing
American Numismatic Society
ANS Record Group 1: Administrative
1853-ongoing
Records relating to the administrative activities of the American Numismatic Society.
133 cubic feet
American Numismatic Society
PORTIONS OF THE FINDING AID ARE SUPPRESSED FROM PUBLIC VIEW. ANS staff can log into Staff View for the full record group description.
Access
Aside from the Biographical Files, most later materials are only for use by ANS personnel.
  nnan0121
- Series: General correspondence, 1853 - 2099; 133 cubic feet
  For similar correspondence from after 1985 see the director and executive director files of Leslie Elam and Ute Wartenberg Kagan and the curatorial files of William E. Metcalf.
  Correspondence; Belden, Bauman L. (Bauman Lowe), 1862-1931; Drowne, Henry Russell, 1860-1934; Poillon, William, 1844-1918; Sage, Augustus B., 1842-1874; Noe, Sydney P. (Sydney Philip), 1885-1969; Wood, Isaac F. (Isaac Francis), 1841-1895
  Consists of the official general correspondence files of the Society from its founding in 1858 to 1985. (Similar correspondence for later years can be found in director, executive director, and chief curator series.)
  The first set (1853, 1858-1908) contains the earliest official correspondence of the American Numismatic Society (known as the American Numismatic and Archeological Society from 1864 to 1907). There are some handwritten copies from Augustus B. Sage, the first corresponding secretary (1858); some handwritten copies in other years (e.g., 1865); a letterpress copybook (1905) and other outgoing copies (1906-1909) from recording secretary Bauman Beldon (1896-1903); and two letterpress copybooks (1874-1896), which include indexes of correspondents, that were kept by recording secretaries William Poillon (1873-1886) and Henry Russell Drowne (1886-1896). The letters document the growth and activities of the Society during a period when it was governed by an unpaid volunteer staff of members and had no permanent home. (The Society moved into its Audubon Terrace headquarters in 1908 and hired its first professional staff in 1909.) Topics include the routine management of members; the issuing of medals, including the Society’s first, which commemorated Abraham Lincoln (1866-1868); the rental of rooms for the society’s business; gifts such as coin cabinets, coins, and books; the development of the numismatic collections; the purchasing of materials for the library, including some librarian’s reports; and matters pertaining to the American Journal of Numismatics. There is only a single letter from 1853, regarding Carolus or “old head” dollars, whose significance regarding the Society is not immediately apparent.
  Additional correspondence later discovered that fits into the early time span of the first set (1853-1908) can be found separate from it. These include Lincoln medal subscription letters (1865-1866); letters and resolutions relating to Gaston L. Feuardent and Luigi Palma di Cesnola (1881-1888); inquiries on coin values (1881, 1908); a letter from engraver William H. Key presumably relating to the Society’s Lincoln medal (1869); correspondence to and from Isaac F. Wood, including one on a donation to the Society’s library in 1886 (1874-1893); a donated letter (1809) from Jacob Perkins, die maker of Massachusetts; and numerous letters from 1902, including from correspondents like George Westinghouse, Cornelius Vanderbilt III, and Archer M. Huntington, mostly regarding membership and committee appointments but sometimes touching on other matters, such as the death of early member William L. Bramhall.
  The correspondence then continues beginning around the time the Society moved into its first permanent home at Audubon Terrace (1908) and hired its first professional staff (1909). Although in the early years there are letters addressed to various ANS figures such as Bauman L. Belden (secretary, 1910-1916) and William Poillon, beginning in the mid-1910s and continuing for a time, most letters are to and from Sydney P. Noe, the Society’s secretary from 1917 to 1947. Various administrators, officials, and curators are represented in later years. Of particular note are the files on various medals issued early in the 20th century: Red Cross, Cardinal Mercier, Catskill Aqueduct, Choate, Declaration of War, Marshal Foch, Hudson-Fulton, Huntington, Independence Day, Joan of Arc, King and Queen of Belgium, LaSalle, Membership, Prince Henry, Prince of Wales, Queen of Belgians, Paul Revere, Algernon S. Sullivan, Americus Vespucci.
  There is a typed index for the letters of the first set of correspondence (1853, 1858-1908), which may have been prepared during the research for Howard L. Adelson’s book for the Society’s centennial in 1958.
  Portions, particularly later materials, are closed to outside researchers. The early correspondence is open.
    nnan0121/c_44a991c4374924d93f7fd967159a6213
  - Box 1.1.1 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 1 of 13)
    Contents:
    1853; 1858; 1859; 1863; 1864; 1865; 1866; 1867; 1868; 1869
  - Box 1.1.2 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 2 of 13)
    1870; 1871; 187; 1873; 1874; 1875; 1876; 1877, January-June; 1877, July-December
  - Box 1.1.3 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 3 of 13)
    1878, January-June; 1878, July-December; 1879, January-June; 1879, July-December; 1880
  - Box 1.1.4 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 4 of 13)
    1881, January-March; 1881, April-December; 1882, January-June; 1882, July-December; 1883, January-April; 1883, May-December
  - Box 1.1.5 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 5 of 13)
    1884, January-March; 1884, April-June; 1884, July-October; 1884, November-December
  - Box 1.1.6 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 6 of 13)
    1885, January-March; 1885, April-December; 1886, January-June; 1886-July-December; 1887.
  - Box 1.1.7 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 7 of 13)
    1888; 1889; 1890; 1891; 1892; 1893, January-June; 1893, July-December
  - Box 1.2.1 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 8 of 13)
    1894, January-June; 1894, July-December; 1895, January-June; 1895, July-December; 1896, January-June; 1896, July-December
  - Box 1.2.2 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 9 of 13)
    1897, January-June; 1897, July-December; 1898, January-June; 1898, July-December; 1899, January-June.; 1899, July-December
  - Box 1.2.3 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 10 of 13)
    1900, January-February; 1900, March-May; 1900, June-August; 1900, September-December; 1900, specific date unknown
  - Box 1.2.4 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 11 of 13)
    1901, January-February; 1901, March; 1901, April-July; 1901, August-December
  - Box 1.2.5 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 12 of 13)
    1902; 1903; 1904; 1905, January-June; 1905, July-December
  - Box 1.2.6 (first set: 1853, 1858-1908 - 13 of 13)
    1906, January-May; 1906, June-December; 1906, Adams’ membership; 1907, January-June; 1907, July-December; 1907, American Journal of Numismatics; 1908, January-July; 1908, September-December
  - Box: Additional General Correspondence (1869-1908)
      nnan0121/c_b2fb4a45f2d727e5776a8460bfeb4b3e
    - Lincoln medal subscription letters, 1865-1866
    - Issac F. Wood correspondence, 1874-1879, 1891-1893
    - Letters to president Charles Anthon regarding coin values, 1881
    - Letter from Mathew A. Stickney including an 1809 letter of Jacob Perkins, 1885
    - Feuardent and Cesnola, 1881-1888
    - Coin inquiries—Mostly to and from corresponding secretary H. Russell Drowne, 1908
    - General ANS correspondence, 1869-1886
    - General ANS correspondence, 1873-1884, 1893, 1895
    - General ANS correspondence, 1896-1901
    - General ANS correspondence, 1902 (3 folders)
  - Box: Additional General Correspondence and Letterpress Copybooks (1874-1896)
  - Box 1.3.1 #1 (ca. 1908-1931)
    A (unsorted)
  - Box 1.3.2 #2 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Abbott, Holker; Abbott, Justin E.; Abel, Anne H.Abo Academy (Finland); Abramson, Engessor Manufacturing Company; Academia Nacional de la Historia (Caracas, Venzuela); Acheson, Edward G.; Ackerman, Ernest R.; Adams, Edgar H., 1908-1912; Adams, Edgar H., 1913; Adams, Edgar H., 1914; Adams, Edgar H., 1915; Adams, Edgar H., 1916-1922; Adams, Edgar H., 1923-1924; Adams, Edward D., 1908-1910; Adams, Edward D., 1911-1914; Adams, Edward D., 1916-1918; Adams, Edward D., 1919-1927
  - Box 1.3.3 #3 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Adams, Elbridge L., 1919-1924; Adams, Herbert; Adams Express Company; Addressograph Company; Administration des Monnaies et Medailles (Paris, France); Aeronautical Society of America.; Agger, E. E. (Rutgers University); Agnew, Andrew G.; Ahlswede, H. Edward.; Aitken, Robert I.; Akron (Ohio) Centennial; Aktiebolaget Nordiska Bokhandeln (Stockholm, Sweden); Albert I (King of Belgium); Alberti, Paul E.; Allen, H. D.; Allen, John.; Allen, William H.; Allis, Charles; Alphonso XIII (King of Spain); Altena, Edward; Alterman, Henry J.; Amelung, Cecilia L.; American Academy of Arts and Letters; American Academy in Rome; American Ambassador, Rome, 1921; American Antiquarian Society (Worchester, Massachusetts); American Art Association.; American Asiatic Association; American Association of Museums, 1923-1928; American Bankers Association Journal; American Consul, Malta; American Express Company; American Express Company; American Federation of Art, 1922-1924; American Foreign Service Corporation; American Geographical Society; American Historical Association; American Institute of Architects; American Institute of Mining and Metallurgical Engineers.
  - Box 1.3.4 #4 (ca. 1908-1931)
    American Journal of Archaeology; American Legion; American Library Association; American Mining Congress; American Museum of Natural History; American News Company; American Numismatic Association (ANA); American Numismatic Association (ANA)—Convention, 1910; American Numismatic Association (ANA)—The Numismatist, 1918-1921
  - Box 1.3.5 #5 (ca. 1908-1931)
    American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Applications for positions; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Building—estimates, 1916; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Christmas appeal, 1924; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Christmas appeal, 1925; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Committees; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Committees; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Committees—Foreign Medals; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Committees—Publications; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Educational posters, ca. 1916
  - Box 1.3.6 #6 (ca. 1908-1931)
    American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medal campaign; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals and publications with a historical sketch; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—American Red Cross; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Cardinal Mercier; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Catskill Aqueduct; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Choate; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Declaration of War; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Marshal Foch; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Hudson-Fulton; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Archer M. Huntington; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Independence Day; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Joan of Arc; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—King and Queen of Belgium Crossing the Channel
  - Box 1.3.7 #7 (ca. 1908-1931)
    American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—LaSalle; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Membership; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Prince Henry of Prussia, 1902; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Prince of Wales; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Queen of Belgians; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Paul Revere; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Algernon S. Sullivan; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Medals—Americus Vespucci
  - Box 1.4.1 #8 (ca. 1908-1931)
    American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Meetings, 1908; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Meetings, 1920s; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Meetings, 1921; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Meetings, 1926; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Meetings, 1929; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Meetings, 1930; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Meetings, 1932; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Membership—Delinquent members; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Membership—Membership campaign, 1918; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Publications; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Reports—Council; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Reports—Council; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Reports—Bd. of Governors; American Numismatic Society (ANS)—Reports—Treasurer, 1925
  - Box 1.4.2 #9 (ca. 1908-1931)
    American Paper Stock Company; American Relief Administration; American Scenic and Historic Preservation Society; American School of Classical Studies (Athens, Greece); American School of Oriental Research (Jerusalem); American Society of Mechanical Engineers; American Surety Company; American University of Beirut; Ames, Oakes; Ames & Rollinson; Anastasis, Augustin G.; Anchor Post Iron Works; Anderson Auction Company; Anderson, Elizabeth M.; Anderson, John S.; Andrew, A. Piatt (Director, U.S. Mint); Andrews, Eugene; Andrews, Frank D.; Andrews, Henry E.; Andrews, J. H. M.; Antiques magazine; Annin & Co., Flag Makers; The Antiquarian magazine; Aplin Vacuum & House Cleaning Co.; Apostolatos, M. E. (coin dealer); Appeals from Germany and German-speaking people; Appleton, W. (New England Society for the Preservation of Antiquities); Archaeological Institute of America; Architectural League of New York; The Arkansas Gazette; Armour & Co.; Arnold, Benjamin Walworth; Arnold, George; Arnot Art Gallery (Almira, New York); Art Alliance of America; Art Association of Indianapolis; Art Framing Co.; Art & Life magazine; Art Institute of Chicago; Art Service; Art World magazine; Artype Press; Arts Council of New York City; Arts and decorations; Ash, Harry A.; Ashton, W. (Mrs.); Association of Military Surgeons of the United States; Astor medal; Astor, Vincent; Atlas Engraving Company; Atlas, Charles A.; Atwater, William G.; Aubert, A.; Aubert, Marcel; Aubin, Leo J.; Audubon Printers; Auer, C. G.; Auerbach, Joseph; Auld, F. H.; Automobile Blue Book; Avery, Samuel P.; Avezzano, Romano (Baron)
  - Box 1.4.3 #10 (ca. 1908-1931)
    B (unsorted)
  - Box 1.4.4 #11 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Babelon, Ernst; Babelon, Jean; Baer, Carlyle S.; Joseph Baer & Co., Buchhaendler und Antiquare; Bahr, Peter; Bahrfeldt, Emil; Bailey, Banks & Biddle Co.; Bailey, James; Bailey, John S; Baird, Andrew B. (Dr.); G. A. Baker & Co.; Baker, Raymond T. (Director, U.S. Mint); Baker, Smith & Co.; Baker, Stephen; Baker & Taylor Co., booksellers, 1923-1924; Baker & Taylor Co., booksellers, 1925; A.H. Baldwin & Sons, Ltd.; L.G. Balfour Co.; Banerji, R. D.; Bangor (Maine) Public Library; Bangs, H. C.; Bank of Pittsburgh; Bankers Trust Co.; Banks, Edgar James; Francis Bannerman Sons; Baranowsky, Michele; Barbi, H.; Barnard F. P. (Curator, Ashmolean Museum); Barnes, W. H.; Barocelli, Piero; Barrett, S. A. (Director, Milwaukee Public Museum); Bartlett, E. E.; Bartlett, Paul; Bartlett, S. A.; Barrington, Rachel T.; Bastian Brothers Co.; Baudez, J. (French Miliary Attache); Bauer, George J.
  - Box 1.4.5 #12 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Beach, Chester; Beal, William; Beardslee, Oliver G.; Beatty, William Gedney; Beaux Arts Institute of Design; Beaux, Cecelia; Beaver, William; Beck, George; Bedel, A. L.; Beekman, Gerard; Beesley, Ebenezer; Beistle, M. L.; Belden, Bauman L.; Belgian Ambassador; Belgian Consul; Queen of Belgium newspaper clippings, 1919; Belgian Legation; Bell, Harold W.; Bell, Rowland; Beller, William; Bellinger, Alfred R.; Belote, Theodore T. (U.S. National Museum); Bement, Clarence S.; Bendann, David; Benjamin, Marcus (U.S. National Museum); Benjamin, Ruth L.; Benet, Jose; Benson, Mary
  - Box 1.4.6 #13 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Berg, Max A.; Berge, Edward; Bernhart, Max (Staatliche Muenzsammlung Muenchen); Berkeley (California) Public Library; Berkowitz, Joseph J.; Berkshire Antheaeum; Berolzheimer, Philip; Berry & Whitmore Co.; Berthold, Victor M.; Better Business Service; Betts, Benjamin; Betts, Samuel R.; Bibliotheque Nationale (Paris, France); Bibliotheque Royale de Belgique (Brussels, Belgium); Bickford H. J.; Biele, Edward; Bierman, Arnold; Biggs, L. A.; Bignell, William (Mrs.); Bills paid, 1919-1921; Bing, Alexander M.; Birchett, J. A. K.; A. & C. Black, Ltd.; Black, E. Titus; Blackburn, J. S. C.; Blackstone Memorial Library; Blake, George H.; Bland, F. A.; Bland, Harry M.; Blanton, Charles A.; Blessing, Arthur (Librarian, Naval War College); Bliss, Robert Woods (Mrs.); Bliss, Tasker H. (General); Blitzblan, Louis; Bloch, H. T.; Block, Karl; Block, Paul; Blodgett, William T.; Bloomingdale, Irving; Bloor, Alfred J.; Bluestone, Barney; Blumenthal, George; Blumenthal, Sidney
  - Box 1.4.7 #14 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Boersenvereins der Deutschen Buchaendler zu Leipzig.Bolton, Reginald P.; Bonaventure, E. F.; Bonnet, Louis.Book dealers; Book, Robert D.; Boone, Cheshire L.; Booth, Franklin; Booth, Henry; Bordas, F.; Borghenzio, Gino. (Societa Piemontese di Archeologia e Belle Arti); Borglum, Gutzon; Borsch, A.; Borst, George H.; Borton, Marjorie Borum, Charles (Jr.); Boss, John B.; Bossom, Alfred C.; Boston Post; Boston Public Library; Boston Numismatic Society; Boston University; Bostwick, W. W.; Bottee, Louis; Bourgey, Etienne; Bourn, W. B.; Bowdoin Museum of Fine Arts; Bowdoin, Temple Bowdoin, W. G.; Bowen, Arthur (State Bank of Chicago); Bowers, George W.; Bowles, Harry S.; Bowman, John M.; Boxstrom, H. J.; Boyd, F. C. C.; Boyer, Alden Scott; Boyle, F.
  - Box 1.5.1 #15 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Bradbury, Harry; Bradlee, F. J.; Brady, Cyrus Townsend; Brand, Joseph; Brandon, Basil; Brassler, Charles A.; Brenner, Judson; Brenner, Victor D., 1896-1924; Brentano’s; Brett, Agnes Baldwin; Brett, George M.; Breyer, Mirko; Briggs, Arthur B.; Bringle, John H.; British Consulate General; British Embassy; British Museum
  - Box 1.5.2 #16 (ca. 1908-1931)
    British Numismatic Society 1906-1908; British Numismatic Society, 1909-1912; British Numismatic Society, 1913-1916; British Numismatic Society, 1919; British Numismatic Society, 1922; British Numismatic Society—Meetings, 1924-1929
  - Box 1.5.3 #17 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Britton, W. Rutger; Brock, Elizabeth; Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences; Brooklyn Public Library; Brooks, Arthur A.; Brooks, Richard E. (Mrs.); Broun-Green Co., printers and stationers, 1924-1925; Brown Brothers; C. H. Brown Co., rug cleaning; Brown, C. Wilson; Brown, F. Q.; Brown, F. Rhinelander; Brown, George F.; Brown, H. B.; Brown, James, public library bookbinder; Brown, Samuel A. (Mrs.); Browning, A. W.; Bruce, O.; Brunner, Arnold W.; Buchenau, (Munzkabinettes Muenchen); Buck, Henrie E.; Buckenham, J. E. B.; Buffalo (NY) Chamber of Commerce.; Buffalo (NY) Historical Society.; Buist, Henry R.; Bulgarian National Museum; Bullen, Henry L.; Bullivant, William M.; Bundessammlung von Medaillen Muenzen und Geldseichen (Vienna, Austria); Burch, Lowell R.; Burgess, Alexander; Burlingham, Charles C.; Burnham, Roger N; Burrage, Russell; Burroughs, E. B. (Rev.); Burrows Brothers Co.; Burruss, A. E.; Burton Historical Collection (Detroit Public Library); Bush-Brown, H. K.; Butler, Charles Stewart; Butler, Dudley; Butler, Howard; Butler, Nicholas M. (Mrs.); Butler, Orma F. (University of Michigan); Butler, Wyckoff & Reid; Butterick Publishing Co.; Butterworth, F. C.
  - Box 1.5.4 #18 (ca. 1908-1931)
    C (unsorted)
  - Box 1.5.5 #19 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Cabanne, Albert; Cable address; Caemmerer, H. P. (Clerk, National Commission of Fine Arts); Carlstrom, Gideon; J. E. Caldwell Co.; Cagiati, Memmo; Cahn, Adolph E.; The Caledonian magazine; Calver, W. L.; Cambridge Encyclopedia Co.; Cambridge University; Cambridge University—Library; Cammann, G. P. (Mrs.); Camp Devons Library; Campbell, William; Campbell, Robert James (Mrs.); Canfield, Harry (Mrs.); Canfield, Frederick A.; Canadian Shipping Agency; Canessa, Ambroglio; Cannon, Henry W.; Capen, Louise; Carnegie Endowment for International Peace; Carnegie Medal; Carnegie Museum (Carnegie Institute); Carp, R.; Carpenter, Elbert (Mrs.); Carpenter, Rhys; Carrington, C. (Mrs.).; Carry, Edward F.; Carter, George R.; Carter, Rice & Co.; Cartier, E. (Belgian ambassador); Cartier, Inc.; Cary Memorial Library (Lexington, Massachusetts); Casa Pardo; Case, Ralph E.; Casey, E. P.; Caskey, L. D. (Curator, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston); Cathcart, Wallace (Western Reserve Historical Society)
  - Box 1.5.6 #20 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Central Book & Newspaper Co.; Central Bureau for Registered Addresses; Century Co. (Century magazine); Cerny, Ernest; Cesano, L. (Instituto Italiano di Numismatica); Chachati, E.; Chadbourne, William M.; Chakallis, Michael K.; Champion, Edouard; Chapman, Henry-Granberg dispute, 1914; Chapman, Henry; Chapman, Henry; Chapman, S. Hudson
  - Box 1.5.7 #21 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Charleston Museum (Charleston, South Carolina); Charon, Costa; Chase National Bank; Chatillon, George E.; Chediak, Manuel A.; Chiera, Edward; Chelsea Neighborhood Association; Chew, Beverly; Chicago Art Institute; Chicago Historical Society; Chicago & Northwestern Railway Co.; Chicago Numismatic Society; Children’s Year Medal; China Society of America; Chinese Consul; Chipman, H. E. H.; Chisolm, George E.; Chivers Book Binding Co.; Christy, Mary L. (Phoenix Public Library); Churchill, E. J. Spencer; Ciani, Louis; Cigerza, Giovanni; Cinelli, Joseph; Circolo Numismatico Napoletano (Naples, Italy); City History Club of New York; City Library Association (Springfield, Massachusetts); Clapp, Charles E.; Clapp, George H.; Clapp, George H.; Clapp, John H.; Clark, James; Clark, L. A.; Clark, P. C.; Clark, T. James; Clark, W. A.; Clark University—Library; Clarke, C. L.; Clarke, John M. (Director, New York State Museum); Classen, Anton H. (Mrs.); The Classical Weekly magazine
  - Box 1.6.1 #22 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Clearwater, Alphonso T.; Cleveland Museum of Art; Cleveland Public Library; Cluett, Sanford L.; Cochran, Alexander Smith; Cockerell, Sydney C. (Curator, Fitzwilliam Museum, Cambridge University); Coggeshall, E. W.; Cohn, Morris (Mrs.); Collins, Fred; Colasanti, Arduino; Cohn, Hans; The Collectors Club; College Art Association of America; Collier’s magazine; Collignon, Arthur; Collins, Edmond J.; Collins, Lathrop; Collins, Ross F.; Columbia University; Columbia University—School for Secretaries; C.R.B. Educational Foundation (Commission for Relief in Belgium); Comparette, T. Louis, 1915-1919; Comparette, T. Louis, 1920-1922; Comstock, William D.
  - Box 1.6.2 #23 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Conference of Historical Societies; Conkling, Mabel; Connecticut Junior Republic Association, 1920; Connecticut State Library; Thomas Cook and Son; Coolidge, Calvin, 1925; Coolidge, Richard, 1925; John E. Cooper & Co., CPAs; Cooper, Morris (Mrs.); Cooper, W. F.; Corbett, Gail S.; Corbino, Cav. (Direzione Generale Delle Antichita e Belle Arti); Cordeal, John F.; Cornell University—Library; Corn Exchange Bank; Corning C. R.; Cosby, Joseph T.; Couch, Eunice B.; Cowell, C. W.; Cowen, William; Count of Santa Eulalia; Country Life magazine; Courteau, Eugene G.; Cramer, Caspar J.; Crane, George F.; Crittenden, William; Crose, John; Crunelle, Leonard; Cruthers, E. E.; Cuban legation; Cunha, Xavier da (Director, Bibliothica Nacional de Lisboa); Cunningham, C. E. (Mrs.); Curtis, George L. (Mrs.); Currelly, C. T. (Royal Ontario Museum of Archaeology); Cutler, Joseph W.
  - Box 1.6.3 #24 (ca. 1908-1931)
    Content:
    D (unsorted)
  - Box 1.6.4 #25 (ca. 1908-1931)